const dataGkGovernmentPlans = [

    {
        question: "What is the role of medium term expenditure framework?",
        optionA: "To help in accounting",
        optionB: "To help in auditing",
        optionC: "To help in establishing tie between planning and budget",
        optionD: "None of above",
        correct: "c"
    },
    {
        question: "In Nepal, which of the following fiscal year is not observed as plan holiday?",
        optionA: "2018/19",
        optionB: "2047/48",
        optionC: "2048/49",
        optionD: "2016/17",
        correct: "d"
    },
    {
        question: "National development council consists of how many members?",
        optionA: "15",
        optionB: "12",
        optionC: "17",
        optionD: "13",
        correct: "b"
    },
    {
        question: "Who is the prime minister to commence and materialize the concept of periodic plan in Nepal?",
        optionA: "Juddha Shamsher",
        optionB: "Tanka Prasad Acharya",
        optionC: "B.P. Koirala",
        optionD: "K.I. Singh",
        correct: "b"
    },
    {
        question: "Which is not the feature of government accounting of Nepal?",
        optionA: "Provision of central and operating level accounting",
        optionB: "Books of account maintained for each budget head",
        optionC: "Use of forms of accounts prepared by FCGO and approved by Auditor general",
        optionD: "Based on single accounting system",
        correct: "d"
    },
    {
        question: "In Nepal internal audit of public office is done by which organization?",
        optionA: "District treasury controller office",
        optionB: "Province treasury controller office",
        optionC: "Internal audit mechanism of local level",
        optionD: "All of above",
        correct: "a"
    },
    {
        question: "Which is the first country in the world to introduce the concept of gender responsive budget?",
        optionA: "USA",
        optionB: "UK",
        optionC: "Austria",
        optionD: "Australia",
        correct: "d"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the full form of LMBIS?",
        optionA: "Local mainstreaming budget information system",
        optionB: "Land management budget information system",
        optionC: "Line ministry budget information system",
        optionD: "None",
        correct: "c"
    },
    {
        question: "Headquarter of INTOSAI is located in which country?",
        optionA: "Vienna Austria",
        optionB: "Jeneva Switzerland",
        optionC: "New York USA",
        optionD: "London UK",
        correct: "a"
    },
    {
        question: "Who is the first finance minister of Nepal to present budget in parliament for most number of times?",
        optionA: "Subarna Shamsher",
        optionB: "Mahesh Acharya",
        optionC: "Ram Sharan Mahat",
        optionD: "Bishnu Paudel",
        correct: "b"
    },
    {
        question: "Among the following which is not the basic element of programme budget?",
        optionA: "Function",
        optionB: "Programme",
        optionC: "Project",
        optionD: "Procedure",
        correct: "d"
    },
    {
        question: "Direct gender responsive budget falls under which category?",
        optionA: "Activities below 50%",
        optionB: "Activities equal to 50%",
        optionC: "Activities above 50%",
        optionD: "Activities between 20 to 50%",
        correct: "c"
    },
    {
        question: "Final audit of public expenditure is done in Nepal by which organization?",
        optionA: "Financial comptroller general office",
        optionB: "Auditor general",
        optionC: "District treasury controller office",
        optionD: "None of above",
        correct: "b"
    },
    {
        question: "New accounting system based on double entry system was introduced in Nepal from when?",
        optionA: "2018 Chaitra 2",
        optionB: "2017 Baisakh 1",
        optionC: "2016 Chaitra 1",
        optionD: "2015 Mangsir 8",
        correct: "a"
    },
    {
        question: "CGAS is ....",
        optionA: "A name of software",
        optionB: "Auditor general form",
        optionC: "Book of account",
        optionD: "None of above",
        correct: "a"
    },
    {
        question: "Single treasury account (TSA) has been implemented in how many districts of Nepal till date?",
        optionA: "72",
        optionB: "75",
        optionC: "77",
        optionD: "74",
        correct: "c"
    },
    {
        question: "Nepal adopted surplus budget in which fiscal year?",
        optionA: "2033/34",
        optionB: "2023/33",
        optionC: "2034/35",
        optionD: "2035/36",
        correct: "a"
    },
    {
        question: "Among the given below which of the following budget emphasizes incrementalism?",
        optionA: "Line item budget",
        optionB: "Program Budget",
        optionC: "Zero based budget",
        optionD: "None of above",
        correct: "a"
    },
    {
        question: "Balanced budget is emphasized by whom?",
        optionA: "Modern economist",
        optionB: "Classical economist",
        optionC: "Neo classical economist",
        optionD: "Neo modern economist",
        correct: "b"
    },
    {
        question: "First budget of Nepal falls under which category?",
        optionA: "Surplus budget",
        optionB: "Deficit budget",
        optionC: "Balanced budget",
        optionD: "Line item budget",
        correct: "b"
    },
    {
        question: "Which is the country in the world to exercise the concept of development planning?",
        optionA: "Russia",
        optionB: "USA",
        optionC: "UK",
        optionD: "Demark",
        correct: "a"
    },
    {
        question: "Performance budgeting is based on ...",
        optionA: "Items of expenditure",
        optionB: "items of investment",
        optionC: "objectives of expenditure",
        optionD: "plan of implementation",
        correct: "c"
    },
    {
        question: "Among the given below which bill is introduced only in house of representatives?",
        optionA: "Money/ Finance Bill",
        optionB: "Civil service bill",
        optionC: "Guthee bill",
        optionD: "Election bill",
        correct: "a"
    },
    {
        question: "Money bill is concerned with which of the following?",
        optionA: "Imposition of tax",
        optionB: "regulation of tax",
        optionC: "alteration of tax",
        optionD: "all of the above",
        correct: "d"
    },
    {
        question: "In how many days national assembly should send back the money bill passed by house of representative and transmitted to national assembly?",
        optionA: "within 10 days",
        optionB: "within 15 days",
        optionC: "within 20 days",
        optionD: "within 30 days",
        correct: "b"
    },
    {
        question: "In how many days national assembly should send back the other bill (except money bill) passed by house of representative and transmitted to national assembly?",
        optionA: "within 15 days",
        optionB: "within 30 days",
        optionC: "within 45 days",
        optionD: "within 60 days",
        correct: "d"
    },
    {
        question: "Among the given below which bill can only be introduced as government bill?",
        optionA: "money bill",
        optionB: "bill concerning a security body",
        optionC: "both",
        optionD: "none",
        correct: "c"
    },
    {
        question: "In which article of present constitution there is provision of estimation of revenue and expenditure of village body and municipality?",
        optionA: "article 228",
        optionB: "article 230",
        optionC: "article 119",
        optionD: "article 207",
        correct: "b"
    },

    {
        question: "Who is the first finance minister to present budget in Nepal?",
        optionA: "Subarna Sumsher",
        optionB: "Mahesh acharya",
        optionC: "Tanka Prasad Acharya",
        optionD: "Ganesh Man Singh",
        correct: "a"
    },
    {
        question: "What was the total estimation in the first annual budget of Nepal presented in 1951?",
        optionA: "Rs. 5,25,29,000",
        optionB: "Rs. 4,25,29,000",
        optionC: "Rs. 5,39,29,000",
        optionD: "Rs. 5,25,59,000",
        correct: "a"
    },
    /* {
        question: "",
        optionA: "",
        optionB: "",
        optionC: "",
        optionD: "",
        correct: ""
    }, */
]


export { dataGkGovernmentPlans }